ARPAN DAS

Student (U.S Citizen)

757 469-5681 • arpan2004.ad@qmail.com • linkedin.com/in/arpan-das-b60a89200/ • 23655 Hopewell Manor Terrace Ashburn, VA 20148

Experience

George Mason University

Research Intern

Fairfax, VA

01/2024 - Present

Supervising Professor: Flavia Colonna, fcolonna@gmu.edu

• Researching the optimal embeddings of a semi-homogenous tree within the hyperbolic disk with the Mason Experimental Geometry Lab. Responsible for generating visualizations of semi-homogenous trees of varying degrees embedded inside the hyperbolic disk using Python.

Astar Explorer Remote

Math Teacher

02/2024 - Present

- · Type: Part-time
- Supervisor: Jean Chang, (571) 619 3478
- Tutor 4th graders via Zoom in various math topics including Geometry, Algebra, fractions and decimals, measurement and conversions, and problem-solving techniques.

Iridium Communications Leesburg, VA

Hardware Intern

05/2023 - 06/2023

- Type: High School Capstone Internship
- Supervisor: Audrey Puderbaugh, (703) 724-8210
- Managed an inventory of equipment and hardware systems using Microsoft Excel. Trained in Attitude Determination and Control Subsystems (ADCS) and
 Orbital Mechanics procedures for satellite launches during the Iridium NEXT 9 launch with SpaceX. Generated visualizations of satellite telemetry using
 Python.

Virginia Space Grant Consortium

NASA Langley Research Center, VA

Cybersecurity Specialist, Virginia Aerospace Science & Technology Scholars

11/2021 - 07/2022

- Type: Summer academy and online course
- Participated in Virginia Aerospace Science & Technology Scholars (VASTS) at NASA Langley Research Center for 1 week. Developed a comprehensive plan
 for cybersecurity and protective measures to be taken during a hypothetical manned mission to Mars. Performed management duties such as allocating
 budgets, deciding crew members, etc. Engaged in a debrief of mission plan with NASA professionals. Engaged in an online course designed to select
 students for the summer academy where I learned about the processes of mission planning, developed spreadsheets for data analysis, performed data
 analysis, performed orbital calculations, and produced many APA-style technical reports.

Education

George Mason University

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, GPA: 3.75

08/2023 - Present

Rock Ridge High School

Advanced High School Diploma, GPA: 4.40

08/2019 - 06/2023

Skills

Python – Java – C# - C - IBM Quantum/Qiskit – Machine Learning – ArcGIS Pro Enterprise – Geospatial Information Systems (GIS) – Unity – Autodesk Fusion 360 – Autodesk Inventor – Ultimaker Cura – Microsoft Office Enterprise – Research – Technical Writing

Summary

Freshman student at George Mason University pursuing a Bachelor of Science in Computer Science with a minor in Physics. Passionate about AI and Machine Learning, Quantum Computing, Robotics, and Astrophysics. Experienced programmer with 4 years of experience in Python, 2 years of experience in Java, and 1 year of experience in C/C#, also acquired experience in hardware systems, orbital mechanics, and data analysis from Iridium Satellite Communications Inc.

Courses and Certificates

CS 262 (Intro to Low-Level Programming), CS 211 (Object Oriented Programing), CS 110 (Essentials of Computer Science) MATH 125 (Discrete Math), MATH 213 (Analytic Geometry & Calculus III), MATH 203 (Linear Algebra), STAT 344 (Probability & Statistics for Engineers).